please Nebuchadnezzar has a dream and in
the stream he forgets what he sees and
Daniel then comes to him and gives him
the dream and I'm not gonna read the
whole thing but you can notice in Daniel
chapter 2 verse 30 verse let's start
with let's go to verse 31 verse 31 the
Bible says thou o King saws and behold a
great Watts a great image and the great
image whose brightness was excellent
stood before thee and the form thereof
was terrible verse 32 the images head
was a fine gold his breast honour and
arms of silver his belly 'no stars of
brass his legs of watts iron and of clay
then verse 44 verse 34 the Bible says
you saw till a stone was cut out without
hands which smote the image upon his
feet that were of iron and clay and
break them to pieces verse 35 then the
the iron the clay the brass the silver
and the gold broken two pieces together
became like the chaff of the summer
threshing floor and the wind that
carried them away that there was no
place found for them what does daniel
tell nebuchadnezzar in this dream he
tells him about an image of a watts
what is the image of is it an image of a
cow now it's an image of a-- of a man
all right I want you to get these two
images of your in your mind one image is
of Jesus Christ who is supposed to be a
reflection or the image of God the other
image also of a man represents what the
nation's the kingdoms Babylon help me
out everyone meet a person Greece and
Rome the question is why does God give
Nebuchadnezzar this dream of an image of
a man by the way come with me to Romans
chapter 1 verse 23
question asking Romans chapter 1 verse
22 and 23
does God condemn the worshipping of
images yeah yeah he does it's very
significant that he gives Nebuchadnezzar
this dream of a man in the form of an
image head of gold chest on the silver
belly and thighs of brass legs of iron
notice what Romans 122 says the Bible
says professing themselves to be wise
they became fools and changed the glory
of the corrupted corruptible God or
uncorruptible God into an image made
like two Watts corruptible man pause
right here what do you think the Bible's
talking about in this verse you know
people that would make images or create
images made like unto corruptible man
what was this in in violation of right
the the second commandment do not a
first commandment actually thou shalt
have no other one gods before me
and so what what the people will do in
the old in in the Old Testament is they
would create these images of corruptible
man to do what worship man now let me
ask you a question
what do you think these nations Babylon
medo-persia Greece and Rome what do you
think they were guilty of they were
guilty of idolatry Naaman asked question
what is idolatry
it's worshiping other gods or it's
worshipping other gods or worshipping
something in the place of God
it is declaring self as it were to be
God I got a question for you this image
in Daniel - is it a good image or a bad
image
think with me is it a good image or a
bad image yeah it's an image that is a
get that is at war with God and God's
people so here you have an image or
almost as it were an idol that was
designed to take the place of God we
might say this is an image of God it was
a word you just use I heard it twice
it's a false image of God check this out
guys who did Satan want to be in heaven
God what is Satan want man to do worship
Him what a Satan one man to see himself
as do you remember what he told Adam and
Eve in the garden you should be one as
God's knowing good and evil you can
become God yourself I have a question
for you do you think that this image in
Daniel 2 could be showing not only the
result of nations that reject God but
also be showing the person who chooses
to set himself up in the image of God
good news and bad news today every one
of us in here is in the image of God let
me say that again every one of us in
here is in the image of God that is good
news but it is also bad news it is good
news if you are in the image of God in
Christ it is bad news if you have set
yourself up as God good news and bad now
beloved listen that you can you are
either one or the other you are either
in the image of God or you are in the
image of God
how many of you want to be in the image
of God you're like which one said I
raised my hand for her how many of you
do not want to put yourself in the image
of God are you are you catching what I'm
saying there are two images beloved one
is the image of Christ dwelling in us in
which case we are truly in the image of
God the other is what this image in
Daniel 2 represents which is the setting
up of self as one's own God this is a
war of images in the Bible it's a war of
images whose image do you bear remember
when Jesus was talking to this to the
the Pharisees came to him and said
should we pay tribute to Caesar you
remember that and Jesus said give me the
coin
and he said whose image is on this they
said Caesars and he said render unto
Caesar that which belongs to Caesar and
unto God that which belongs to God
beloved there are only two images in the
world there is the image of man as God
and there's the image of Christ as God
the question is which image do we bear
[Music]
which image are we reflecting I want to
share with you some some some really
interesting things about this image in
Daniel 2 because if we understand this
image of a man as the image of of an
evil man image of a man of sin you
remember that in the book of second
Thessalonians chapter 2 let's go there
let's get it up on the screen if we can
second Thessalonians chapter 2 verses 1
through 4 the Bible says here now we
beseech you brethren by the coming of
our Lord Jesus Christ and by our
gathering together unto Him that you be
not soon shaken in mind or be troubled
neither by spirit nor by word nor by
letter as from us as that the day of
Christ is at hand
notice verse three let no man deceive
you by any means for that day shall not
come except there come a falling away
first and that man of what man of sin be
revealed the son of perdition notice
what it goes on to say who exposes and
exalted himself above all that is called
God or that is worshipped so that he as
who God sits in the temple of God
showing himself to be God I got a simple
question for you when you look at this
image in Daniel chapter 2 do you see a
symbol a type of the man of sin
absolutely and remember the man of sin
even though we look at the man of sin as
a religious entity that is going to be
fully manifested by the end of time the
ultimate man of sin is Satan himself and
check this out because I never saw this
before but do you realize it if you look
at the characteristics of this image in
Daniel 2 for example did Nebuchadnezzar
want to be worshipped
Daniel 3 is that correct in the middle
Persian Empire the darius fall for this
thing about praying to no other god but
to him do you see those two things
happening with lucifer in heaven
absolutely in fact if you go to the
Grecian Empire and it's really
interesting because the Bible you know
the Bible talks about what happened in
Babylon with the Jews and what happened
with Greece I'm sorry and meet a person
with the Jews but it doesn't really did
describe what happened to the Jews in
great detail under the Grecian Empire
but there is something that happened to
the Jews under the Grecian Empire how
many you ever heard of hellenization
okay that's where the Greek Empire
basically the way it is said is that
they Hellenized the Jews in other words
they got
except Greek culture Greek philosophy
the sciences arts they humanize the Jews
this is where a compromise began to come
into Judaism they were Hellenized they
were held the niced they were Hellenized
they were they were persuaded to begin
to to compromise their position their
truths let me ask a question
didn't Lucifer do that to angels in
heaven absolutely when you get down to
the Roman Empire what did Rome stand out
for what was the major offense of Rome
what was the major thing that Ron did
they went to war with whom just not the
Jews but with Jesus Christ himself
is this what Lucifer did in heaven in
other words but if you look at the image
of Daniel - and the things that were an
offense to God throughout the empires of
this image you can basically see the
same thing is what Lucifer did in heaven
which is what led to the fall of Lucifer
from heaven now do you think Lucifer
wants you to make those same mistakes
what do you think do you think Lucifer
is trying to recreate you in the image
of Daniel chapter 2 in his image which
means you putting yourself in the place
of who of God you know as I was looking
at this image and there's something that
that that kind of jumped out to me that
I never looked at before but this is
really amazing because you understand
that every aspect of this image Babylon
medo-persia Greece Rome they were all in
different ways warring against the
people of God warned
the Jews and 2a2 and we can pretty much
say that their war against the Jews was
successful why would we say that why
would we say that their war against the
Jews was successful against God's people
in the Old Testament was successful
because when the ultimate test came
which was Jesus himself coming to his
people what did the Jews do they
crucified him
in other words Satan's attack on the
people of God from the Babylonian Empire
all the way down to Rome
somehow or another led them to the place
where when Christ came they did not even
recognize him as the Messiah and I was
thinking how could they have done this
thing and as I was looking at that image
it was almost as if the very image
itself was revealing the sin of God's
people you say pastor what do you mean
let me ask you tell me about the image
again what was the head of what was the
chest of the legs are of bra of the
belly and thighs are of brass and the
legs were of iron it is as if God used
these very medals to be a rebuke to the
children of Israel who knows what gold
stands for in the Bible faith faith
tried by fire that's what first Peter
says right it's as if God was saying
listen the reason why you are failing is
because you are not exercising faith in
me how about silver what does silver
representing the Bible silver represents
the Word of God let's get this up on the
screen I want you to notice Psalm
chapter 12 verse 6 the words of the Lord
are pure words as watts silver tried in
a furnace of Earth purified seven times
it's as if God was saying listen the
reason why this enmity why this
punishment is coming upon you is because
you do not exercise faith in me
you do not exercise faith in my word how
about brass I want you to notice this
isaiah 40:8 verse 4 God speaking here
says because I knew that thou art what
obstinate and thy neck is as in iron
sinew and eyebrow as what does that
represent what does Brett what do brass
and iron represent obstinacy
stubbornness it's as if God was saying
listen the reason that you are being
persecuted the reason that that you are
are being held captive the reason why
you are not fulfilling my mission for
you is because you have not exercised
faith you do not trust in my word and
you're stubborn and hard-hearted but if
that characteristic describes you that
makes you the image in Daniel chapter 2
it's not just about Babylon medo-persia
Greece and Rome but on a very personal
level have I made myself into God have I
made myself my own God whatever the
question is whose image are you in are
you in the image of God or are you in
the image of Christ I want you to notice
this as well Babylon attacked the law
did they not they wanted to set up an
image and command and everyone a bow
down and so and so they were attacking
the law of God because there's a law
that says thou shalt not worship graven
images so Babylon attacked the law meter
Persia did they attack prayer yeah
remember the decree no one can pray to
any other God except Darius what in
Greece do we just said at Greece what do
they do they they basically led the Jews
to compromise their faith and roll
we said that as well what did Ron do
they crucified Christ let me sum that up
for you if you find yourself fighting
against the law of God what is the law
how many of you fight would say I fight
against the law of God I don't think
anyone in here would say they fight
against the law of God because we all
believe in the Ten Commandments amen
amen amen
yeah but when we realize that Jesus says
the law is summarized in one word which
is love now how many of us might
consider yeah I may be fighting against
the law of God because you see beloved
if you don't love your neighbor if you
don't love your enemy you are fighting
against the law of God you are that head
of gold you not Nebuchadnezzar you you
are that image when God says come let's
pray together reason together and you
say no I'm not gonna pray I don't want
to pray that you are that image if you
find yourself adopting worldly
principles and policies the
hellenization of the Jews you are that
image if you find yourself fighting
against Christ you are that image you
have set yourself up in the image of God
the question is beloved whose image are
you in how many of you are in God's
image how many of you are in God's image
that was question part 2 now you don't
know what to do you're like I'm not sure
but beloved God is calling us to
consider these things because it is
crucial that we understand
setting myself up in the place of God
Exodus 32 verse 13 I need you to see
this Exodus chapter 32 verse 13 the
Bible says remember Abraham Isaac and
Israel thy servants to whom thou
swear'st by thine own self and said unto
them I will multiply your Watts as the
stars of heaven and all this land that I
have spoken of will I give unto your
what seed that they shall inherit it for
ever
what does God call Israel here what is
he calling seed so let me see if you get
this everyone raising I do understand is
Israel is seed in God's eyes yes all
right what did God do with the seed of
Israel when they began to rebel first
Kings chapter 14 verse 15 first Kings
chapter 14 verse 15 for the Lord shall
smite Israel as a reed is shaken in the
water and he saw root up Israel out of
this good land which he gave to their
fathers and shall want
so what did God do with the seed Israel
when they began to rebelled he what he
scattered them so would you say that God
was the scatterer
of the seed of Israel yes he scattered
them amen
come come come with me Matthew chapter
13 Matthew chapter 13 in fact don't go
to Matthew 13 first I need you to go to
Daniel chapter 1 Daniel chapter 1 I want
you to notice verses 3 through 6 let's
get it up on the screen Daniel chapter 1
verse 3 through 6 and the kings speak
unto astronauts the master of his
eunuchs that he should bring certain of
the children of Israel and of the Kings
seed and of the princess of pause right
there who was part of the king's seed
Daniel Shadrach Meshach and Abednego so
what happened to the seed of Israel
where were they scatter
to babylon now come with me to Matthew
chapter 13 Matthew chapter 13 and it's a
parable that most of you if not all of
you know Matthew chapter 13 verse 3
Matthew chapter 13 verse 3 and the Bible
says and he speak many things unto them
in parables saying behold a sower a
scatterer a sower went forth two walks
two so to scatter verse four and when he
sowed some seeds fell by the way side
and the fowls came and devoured them up
now pause right here how many of you
know the parable okay how many grounds
are there how many grounds are there
how they're six you bout to throw my
sermon off man very good very good very
good
all right you you're good I'm with you
I'm with you right in the good ground
there's some that bring for 30 60 etc
but ultimately there are four four
places in which the seed was sown I
don't know if you guys are following
this four places Babylon medo-persia
Greece and Rome and what's interesting
about this beloved you got to see this
because because remember in the first
ground River these are an order ground
long ground to ground three ground for
and listen carefully it's in ground
floor it's in ground for that there is a
fruitful harvest ground one check this
out
remembering ground one it says and when
he sold some seed fell by the way side
and the fowls came and devoured them up
now Jesus explains this by saying in
verse eighteen and nineteen he says here
he therefore the parable of the know in
fact before we read verse 13 verse 18
let me go to verse 11 and I'll read this
in your hearing he answered them and
said remember they asked them why do you
speak in parables he answered them and
said because it is given unto you to
know the mysteries of the kingdom of
heaven but to them it is not given for
who server have to him shall be given
and he shall have more abundance but
whosoever has not from heals from him
shall be taken away even as he has not
therefore i speak to them in parables
because they seeing what see not and
what else hearing they hear not or do
not understand and in denis fulfill the
prophecy
of Isaiah which saith by hearing ye
shall hear and shall not understand and
seeing ye shall see and shall not
perceived for this people's heart is
waxed gross and their ears are dull of
hearing okay so why is Jesus quoting
Isaiah well Isaiah spoke these very
words to the children of Israel as they
were about to or experience captivity in
Babylon do you catch what I just said
listen Matthew 13 verse 18 it says this
here you therefore the parable when
anyone here at the word of the kingdom
and understandeth it not then cometh the
wicked one and catcheth away that which
was sown in his heart this is he which
received seed by the wayside
so who are they never seen see by the
wayside those who hear the word of God
but don't want understand it let me ask
you a question
did God send profits to Israel to warn
them of their rebellion does Isaiah say
himself that Israel heard but did not
want understand Isaiah 51 verse 34
Isaiah 51 verse 34 check out what the
Bible says here what happened to the
seed on the on by the wayside the birds
came and did what what did they do they
devoured it up notice Jeremiah chapter
53 Jeremiah chapter 51 verse 34
Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon has
what has what who is the me spoken of
here speaking of Israel Nebuchadnezzar
king of Babylon has devoured me he has
crushed me and he has made an empty
vessel and has swallowed me up like a
dragon he has filled his belly with my
delicacies he has cast me out do you
understand that when God was sowing
the seed of Israel in Babylon not only
was it a punishment but it was also to
try to get them to open their eyes it
was also for them to see their own sins
and ultimately be used to bring glory to
God in Babylon did they succeed or did
they fail did they succeed or did they
fail
yeah they failed except for Daniel
Shadrach Meshach and Abednego the seed
of Israel failed what about that second
ground the second ground some fell upon
stony places they had not much earth and
forthwith they sprung up because they
had no deepness of earth and when the
Sun was up they were scorched and
because they had no root they withered
away that's Matthew 13 verse 5 and 6
Jesus explains that by saying he that
received the seed in stony places the
same is he that hears the word and with
joy receives it yet he has no root in
himself but dureth for a while for when
tribulation or persecution arises
because of the word by and by he's
offended some ask you a question if the
first ground that Jesus planted the seed
in was Babylon the second ground would
be what needle person was there any
reason for Israel to have joy when the
meat when the medo-persian kingdom came
on the scene the Bible actually
prophesied that Cyrus would come and he
would give for them the spirit of joy
for mourning why because he was going to
set them free to go do something to go
build a temple but let me ask you a
question did they ultimately get
discouraged from building the temple why
no roots and were they being persecuted
were they able to build the temple
freely or did they fail persecution they
faced it they faced persecution and
because of that persecution they became
discouraged and did
really did not fulfill what God wanted
them to fulfill except for a few
you remember Nehemiah comes upon the
scene and he ultimately finishes the
work but even then the Jews hearts were
hardening and if you read what the
spirit of prophecy says about this event
she says that there when they finished
building the temple there were some who
shouted for joy and some who wept with
bitterness because they felt the glory
of the first of the Second Temple did
not match the glory of the first and she
said little did they realize the
damaging effect of their bitter and
complaining spirit upon Israel okay what
about the third ground the third ground
and some fell among thorns and the
thorns sprung up and choked them Jesus
describes it in this way he says he that
received seed among the thorns is he
that hear the word and the care of this
world and the deceitfulness of riches
choke the word and he becomes unfruitful
what's happening to this third group
what's happening with them give it to me
Allah give it to me in your own words
what's happening with this group okay
they're becoming feminized they're
becoming hell an eyes they're beginning
to see things the way the world sees it
and now the cares of the world is what
overtakes them versus the cares of
heavenly things but then there's one
more groan and what of it is in this
ground that Christ the seed who is he
the seed comes and he is planted in this
ground during this Kingdom and beloved
praise God because of Christ's death
burial and resurrection he brought forth
fruit 30 60
beloved you have to understand it's the
reason that Jesus came into this world
was to save us from ourselves
was to save us from the image of God the
false image of God that we had set up
for ourselves
so Christ comes to this world and says
I'm gonna show you what the true image
of God looks like Israel I want you to
do this but in Babylon you failed in
meet a person you failed in Greece you
failed so I am coming now in this fourth
time in this fourth period of time and
I'm going to plant myself and through my
death burial and resurrection I'm gonna
demonstrate to you what the true image
of God is like and beloved when man sees
this true image of God and by the way I
need you to understand this because it
was a war of images when the true image
of God came the counterfeit image of God
did everything in its power to try to
get the true image of God to fall
tempting him in the wilderness upon the
cross come down and whatever he could do
to get this true image of God to fall so
that only one image would dominate
planet Earth and that is an image of
Daniel 2 but Christ overcame and as a
result because of his death burial and
resurrection he says now in me you can
die be buried and resurrected and you
could have my image in you and check
this out guys I'm getting ready to close
listen carefully how was the image
destroyed the stone and something else
the stone and the wind the image was
destroyed the old image the old man the
man of sin was destroyed by the stone
and the wind no Fuhrer who is the stone
in Daniel chapter 2 it is Jesus what is
the wind in Daniel chapter 2 it is his
spirits beloved when we give our lives
to Christ we allow the stone and the
wind to come and destroy the counterfeit
image of God in us
in other words beloved the Holy Spirit
which which brings the fruit of the
Spirit love joy peace long-suffering
gentleness goodness faith meekness
temperance those are the things that
destroys the image which means if you
don't have love if you don't have joy if
you don't have peace if you don't have
the fruit of the Spirit if you are not
demonstrating that fruit of the Spirit
you are in the image of Daniel chapter 2
you are the image of Daniel chapter 2
you are that man of sin the more you
continue beloved to live in that image
of Daniel chapter 2 is the more you
reflect that character you become absent
of love joy peace longsuffering you
become absent of these things and not
even in church can you demonstrate these
things you are bound to act like the man
of sin even in church you can't even
come to church and worship any longer
why because the man of sin
but I would if you don't have the Spirit
of God dwelling in you if we don't have
the Spirit of God dwelling in us the bad
news is you are in the image of God if
you allow the Spirit of God to enter
into your life and exercise those fruit
the fruit of the Spirit the good news is
you are in the image of God so I'll
close with this very simple appeal of it
would you rather be in the image of God
or will you settle to be in the image of
God which one do you want because we are
all one or the other
whose image do you bear whose image do
you bear